Kotschnig, Walter Maria; Papers ger053
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Correspondence, 1927-1984; 2; 1402 folders
  - General correspondence, individuals, organizations, 1932-1975; 2.4
    - Pooley, Richard P., 1938; 2 items (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 179)
    - Porges, Franziska, 1939-1941; 4 items (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 180)
    - La Prensa (Dariel F. Steer), 1942-1943; 8 items (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 181)
    - Price, Helen E., 1940-1941; 4 items (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 182)
    - Puech, J. L., 1937; 2 items (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 183)
    - Putnam, B. H., 1939; 3 items (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 184)
    - Rager, Frederick (Fritz), 1937-1944; 28 items (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 185)
    - Raible, Robert, 1941-1943; 3 items (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 186)
    - Randall, Helen, 1939; 2 items (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 187)
    - Redefer, Frederick (Progressive Education Association, P.E.A), 1942; 3 items (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 188)
    - Reed, Alfred Z. (The Carnegie Foundation for the Advancement of Teaching), 1935-1940; 18 items (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 189)
    - Refugee Relief Trustees, Inc. (Henry E. Muller), 1944; 2 items (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 190)
    - Rehrmann, Leslie Beckett (The World Youth Movement), 1943-1946; 6 items (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 191)
    - Revell, Ethel, 1943; 2 items (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 192)
    - Richter, Werner, 1939; 2 items (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 193)
    - Riegelman, Carol (International Labor Office), 1937-1951; 7 items (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 194)
    - Riegner, Helene, 1938-1939; 2 items (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 195)
    - Riggs, Ernest W., 1943-1944; 10 items (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 196)
    - Ritchie, Frank (The American Christian Committee for German Refugees), 1936-1939; 8 items (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 197)
    - Robb, Rosalind, Undated (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 197)
      See Salant, Rosalind Robb.
    - Rockefeller, Nelson A., 1941; 1 item (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 198)
    - Roosevelt, Franklin D., 1943; 1 item (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 199)
    - Rosenstock-Huessy, Eugen, 1938-1942; 6 items (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 200)
    - Rous, Peyton, 1940; 2 items (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 201)
    - Roy, Ida, 1942; 3 items (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 202)
    - Rugg, Harold, 1943; 1 item (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 203)
    - Sadler, Sir Michael, 1937-1943; 6 items (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 204)
    - Salant, Rosalind Robb, 1940-1941; 4 items (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 205)
    - Salat, Rudi (Pax Romana), 1939; 7 items (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 206)
    - Sangree, Eleanor, 1943; 4 items (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 207)
    - Sargent, Porter, 1943-1944; 4 items (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 208)
    - Sawyer, Olive, 1936-1943; 8 items (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 209)
    - Sayre, John Nevin (The Fellowship of Reconciliation), 1938; 3 items (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 210)
    - Schairer, Reinhold (United States Committee on Educational Reconstruction), 1939-1943; 23 items (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 211)
    - Schalet, Beatrice B., 1939; 2 items (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 212)
    - Schickele, Rainer, 1938; 1 item (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 213)
    - Schmid, R. C., 1939; 2 items (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 214)
    - Schnitzler, Heinrich, 1941; 2 items (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 215)
    - Schönfeld, Hans (Universal Christian Council for Life and Work), 1936; 2 items (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 216)
    - Schoolmen's Week Proceedings, 1939-1940; 10 items (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 217)
    - Schuman, Frederick, 1940; 4 items (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 218)
    - Schuschnigg, Walter von, 1941-1942; 9 items (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 219)
    - Schwarz, Ernst (The Good Neighbor, International Forum for Pan-American Friendship and Democratic World Cooperation), 1938; 2 items (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 220)
    - Seamans, Herbert L. (The National Conference of Christians & Jews), 1939; 2 items (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 221)
    - Secondary Education (Ernest D. Lewis), 1939; 2 items (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 222)
    - Selfhelp of Emigres from Central Europe, Inc., 1940-1942; 7 items (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 223)
    - Selig, Anna, 1931; 1952; 2 items (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 224)
    - Sell, F. C., 1940-1941; 11 items (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 225)
    - Shepard, Brooks, 1943; 4 items (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 226)
    - Sherman, Harold C., 1939; 1 item (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 227)
    - Sherman, Virginia Brillinger, 1940; 2 items (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 228)
    - Shils, Edward A., 1938; 1 item (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 229)
    - Shotwell, James T. (Carnegie Endowment for International Peace), 1934-1950; 50 items (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 230)
    - Schultz, Earl N., 1936; 1 item (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 231)
    - Silver, Lavina, 1940; 2 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 1)
    - Simm, E. D., 1936; 1 item (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 2)
    - Simmel, Marianne, 1940; 4 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 3)
    - Simon, Abbott, 1939; 2 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 4)
    - Simpson, Esther (Society for the Protection of Science and Learning), 1938; 2 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 5)
    - Simsarian, Arax, 1943; 2 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 6)
    - Singsen, Antone G., 1940; 1 item (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 7)
    - Skeels, Lynn, 1941-1942; 2 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 8)
    - Slotemaker de Bruine, Nicolas (The Netherlands Information Bureau), 1942-1943; 14 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 9)
    - Smiley, Marjorie B., 1943; 2 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 10)
    - Smith College, 1937-1944; 98 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 11)
    - Smith, Elna N. (Works Progress Administration), 1939; 2 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 12)
    - Smith, Harry C., 1942; 4 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 13)
    - Smith, J. Russell, 1937; 2 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 14)
    - Smith, Temperence (Terry; Carnegie Endowment for International Peace), 1938-1941; 12 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 15)
    - Snyder, Gerald W., 1942; 2 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 16)
    - Social Education (Erling M. Hunt), 1941-1944; 16 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 17)
    - Society for the Advancement of Education, 1939; 3 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 18)
    - Solomon, Lillian, 1937; 2 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 19)
    - Soule, Anne L., 1939; 2 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 20)
    - Sousa, John Philip III, 1943; 1 item (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 21)
    - Spaulding, Francis T., 1939; 2 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 22)
    - Spaulding, Susan, 1939; 2 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 22)
    - Speare, Elizabeth, 1941; 2 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 23)
    - Spencer, Harry C., 1943; 2 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 24)
    - Spencer, Imogene H., 1938; 1 item (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 25)
    - Spiegelberg, Friedrich, Undated; 1 item (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 26)
    - Spring, Leo, 1938; 2 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 27)
    - Staudinger, Else (American Committee for Refugee Scholars, Writers and Artists, 1945; 2 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 28)
    - Steckler, Edward L., 1944; 5 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 29)
    - Steinberg, Charles Side (Book-of-the-Month Club), 1943; 6 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 30)
    - Stephens, Isabel McL, 1941; 2 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 31)
    - Stephens, Margaret (International Federation of University Women), 1938; 2 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 32)
    - Stephenson, Mary Cheney, 1938-1943; 7 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 33)
    - Stern-Sober, Lila, 1941; 2 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 34)
    - Sterne, Emma Gelders, 1943; 3 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 35)
    - Stewart, Ann C., 1940-1943; 36 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 36)
    - Stewart, Lucile Emerson, 1941; 3 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 37)
    - Stewart, Virginia, 1942-1943; 10 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 38)
    - Stinnes, Edmund H., 1944; 2 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 39)
    - Stirling, Janet R., 1942; 2 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 40)
    - Stoddard, Alexander J. (The Educational Policies Commission), 1943; 6 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 41)
    - Stoke, Stuart M., 1937-1944; 37 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 42)
    - Stott, Gilmore (Committee to Defend America by Aiding the Allies), 1940-1941; 5 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 43)
    - Stratton, E. Gwynn, 1945; 2 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 44)
    - Strebel, Ralph F., 1943-1944; 8 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 45)
    - Streib, Gordon, 1941; 1 item (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 46)
    - Streit, J., 1940; 2 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 47)
    - Strong, Corrin, 1940; 2 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 48)
    - Studebaker, John W. (U.S. Department of the Interior), 1936-1943; 22 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 49)
    - Student Peace Service, American Friends Service Committee (Harold Chance, Philip Jacob), 1937-1938; 9 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 50)
    - Su, Frank Kai-Ming, 1938; 2 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 51)
    - Suffrin, Marsha E. (Peggy), 1942-1943; 5 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 52)
    - Suizo, Charles Jr., 1941; 2 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 53)
    - Sulzberger, Arthur Hays (New York Times), 1939; 3 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 54)
    - Survey Associates (Paul Kellogg), 1939-1940; 5 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 55)
    - Swain, Loring, 1941; 2 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 56)
    - Tabouis, Geneviève, 1944; 1 item (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 57)
    - Tait, D. Christie (International Labour Office), 1937; 8 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 58)
    - Tatlock, June M., 1941; 2 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 59)
    - Tatlow, Tissington, 1934-1943; 9 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 60)
    - Taylor, Mary Louise, 1939; 2 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 61)
    - Tead, Ordway (Harper & Brothers), 1943-1944; 1953; 9 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 62)
      See also Nostrand, Howard Lee.
    - Teich, Alexander, 1938-1960; 20 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 63)
    - Teich, Anna, Undated (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 63)
    - Terman, E. L., 1938; 2 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 64)
    - Thomas, Frances A. (Commission to Study the Organization of Peace; League of Nations Association, Inc), 1940-1944; 39 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 65)
    - Thomas, Harold P., 1938; 1 item (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 66)
    - Thomas, Mary Carr, 1943; 4 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 67)
    - Thomas, Prentice, 1941; 2 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 68)
    - Thompson, Dorothy, 1941-1942; 2 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 69)
    - Tillich, Paul, 1938-1941; 8 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 70)
    - Time (Leona Carney), 1942-1943; 3 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 71)
    - Tomlinson, William W., 1944; 1 item (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 72)
    - Toomey, Ursula K., 1940; 2 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 73)
    - Towle, Gifford, 1938; 2 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 74)
    - Traister, Sarahla E., 1943; 2 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 75)
    - Trowbridge, Buel, 1940; 1949; 9 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 76)
    - True, Peggy, 1943; 2 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 77)
    - Tucker, Prudence (The Hartford Courant), 1943; 2 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 78)
    - Turle, Penelope, 1941; 2 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 79)
    - Turner, Carol, 1939; 3 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 80)
    - Turner E. Smith & Company, 1942; 1 item (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 81)
    - Turner, J. W. Cecil, 1940-1942; 12 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 82)
    - Ulich, Robert, 1936-1944; 42 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 83)
    - The University of Chicago Press (W. K. Jordan), 1942; 4 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 84)
    - University of Minnesota (W. E. Peik), 1938-1941; 31 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 85)
    - U. S. Office of Education (Marjorie S. Scott), 1943; 11 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 86)
    - Valentin, Veit, 1939; 1943; 7 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 87)
    - Veatch, Roy (Department of State), 1943; 1 item (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 88)
    - Visser 't Hooft, W. A. (World's Student Christian Federation), 1937; 2 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 89)
    - Vlekke, Bernard H. M., 1942; 1 item (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 90)
    - Voukitchevitch, Vladita, 1936; 3 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 91)
    - Wagner, Viola E., 1942; 2 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 92)
    - Waite, Mary L., 1938; 4 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 93)
    - Wakeman, Seth, 1938-1953; 51 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 94)
    - Waldinger, Theodor, 1939; 2 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 95)
    - Waldo, Alice (The American Committee for Christian German Refugees), 1937; 2 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 96)
    - Walker, Gladys R., 1938; 3 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 97)
    - Walsh, David I., 1943; 2 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 98)
    - Warburg (Grimson), Bettina, 1937-1943; 6 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 99)
    - Warburg, Felix M., 1937; 2 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 100)
    - Warburg, Frieda Schiff, 1937; 1 item (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 100)
    - Warburg, Max M., 1943; 2 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 101)
    - Warren, George L. (President's Advisory Committee on Political Refugees), 1939-1942; 5 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 102)
    - Watt, Donald B. (The Experiment in International Living, Inc), 1942; 3 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 103)
    - Weiden, Gerda M., 1938; 1943; 7 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 104)
    - Weiner, Emanuel, 1936; 1 item (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 105)
    - Wells, Dorothy P., 1943; 2 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 106)
    - Wells, Edward H., 1943; 1 item (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 107)
    - Wendlberger, J., 1939; 1 item (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 108)
    - Weston, Harold (Food for Freedom, Inc), 1942-1943; 31 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 109)
    - Wheeler, Florence Lillie, 1943; 3 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 110)
    - Wheeler, J. A., 1942; 1 item (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 111)
    - Whiting, Elizabeth G. (The Council for Social Action of the Congregational Christian Churches of the United States of America), 1942; 1 item (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 112)
    - Who's Who, 1942-1975; 10 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 113)
    - Whyte, John, 1937-1940; 7 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 114)
    - Wickmar, A. H., 1942; 2 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 115)
    - Wild, Laura H., 1943; 2 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 116)
    - Wilde, Louise K. (Billy), 1938-1957; 20 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 117)
    - Wilder, Winifred, 1938-1943; 7 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 118)
    - Wilkens, Ernest H., 1939; 4 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 119)
    - Wilkenson, Winifred, 1943; 5 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 120)
    - Willard, Edward Francis, 1941; 1 item (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 121)
    - Willert, Paul (Oxford University Press), 1937-1939; 23 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 122)
    - Willey, Malcolm M., 1939-1942; 4 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 123)
    - Williams, Chester S. (Office of War Information), 1942-1943; 13 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 124)
    - Wilmer, Florence C., 1943; 2 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 125)
    - Wilson, Howard E. (Harvard Educational Review), 1938-1946; 35 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 126)
    - Winkler, Evemarie, 1940; 1 item (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 127)
    - Winter, Ernst Karl, 1939-1940; 10 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 128)
    - Wolf, George V., 1940; 2 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 129)
    - Wolf, Richard, 1939; 1 item (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 130)
    - Wolff, Renate, 1942-1943; 11 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 131)
    - Wood, Richard, 1943; 1 item (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 132)
    - Wooley, Mary E. (Mount Holyoke College), 1936-1943; 22 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 133)
    - Women's National Institute, 1942; 1 item (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 134)
    - World Confederation of International Groupments, 1942; 3 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 135)
    - World Youth Tour (Mary Frank Mason), 1938; 4 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 136)
    - Wright, Alice Morgan (National Woman's Party), 1945; 2 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 137)
    - Wunderlich, Frieda, 1940; 2 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 138)
    - Wurfbain, André, 1936; 2 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 139)
    - Wyatt, Gertrude L., 1940; 2 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 140)
    - Wygal, Winnifred, 1939-1940; 4 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 141)
    - Yates, Mildred, 1939; 2 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 142)
    - Zook, George F. (American Council on Education), 1937-1950; 68 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 143)
  - General correspondence, arranged by subject, 1928-1952; 2.5
    - Immigration and naturalization, 1936-1938; 20 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 144)
    - Immigration and naturalization, 1940-1941; 17 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 145)
    - Immigration and naturalization, 1942-1943; 65 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 146)
    - Educational reconstruction, post-war Germany, 1940-1944; 76 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 147)
    - Employment, 1936; 13 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 148)
    - Recommendations, 1938-1943; 28 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 149)
    - Travel arrangements, 1928-1952; 28 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 150)
    - Slaves Need No Leaders, 1942-1943; 45 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 151)
    - Unemployment in the Learned Professions, 1934-1938; 1944; 62 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 152)
    - "The University in a Changing World", 1935; 1937; 2 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 153)
    - Miscellaneous, 1936; 8 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 154)
    - Miscellaneous, 1937; 10 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 155)
    - Miscellaneous, 1938; 27 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 156)
    - Miscellaneous, 1939; 63 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 157)
    - Miscellaneous, 1940; 35 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 158)
    - Miscellaneous, 1941; 33 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 159)
    - Miscellaneous, 1942; 30 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 160)
    - Miscellaneous, 1943; 43 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 161)
    - Miscellaneous, 1944-1950; 14 items (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 162)
  - Correspondence concerning speaking engagements, 1933-1946; 1954-1956; 2.6; 28 folders
    This series contains Kotschnig's correspondence (circa 1745 items) with organizations and institutions concerning arrangements for his lecture engagements, predominately dating from the years 1937-1944.
    - Lectures, 1933-1936; 4 items (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 1)
    - Lectures, 1937; 49 items (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 2)
    - Lectures declined, 1937; 22 items (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 3)
    - Lectures, 1938 January-1938 May; 94 items (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 4)
    - Lectures, 1938 June-1938 December; 63 items (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 5)
    - Lectures declined, 1938; 27 items (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 6)
    - Lectures, 1939 January-1939 May; 157 items (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 7)
    - Lectures, 1939 June-1939 December; 37 items (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 8)
    - Lectures declined, 1939; 22 items (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 9)
    - Lectures, 1940; 115 items (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 10)
    - Lectures declined, 1940; 29 items (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 11)
    - Lectures, 1941; 98 items (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 12)
    - Lectures declined, 1941; 38 items (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 13)
    - Lectures, 1942 January-1942 June; 130 items (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 14)
    - Lectures, 1942 July-1942 December; 83 items (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 15)
    - Lectures declined, 1942; 21 items (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 16)
    - Lectures, 1943 January-1943 April; 98 items (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 17)
    - Lectures, 1943 May-1943 September; 100 items (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 18)
    - Lectures, 1943 October-1943 December; 148 items (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 19)
    - Lectures declined, 1943; 84 items (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 20)
    - Lectures, 1944 January-1944 March; 97 items (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 21)
    - Lectures, 1944 April-1944 June; 118 items (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 22)
    - Lectures declined, 1944-1946; 56 items (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 23)
    - A. H. Hanley Concert and Lecture Management, 1944; 5 items (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 24)
    - The Alumnae Association of Smith College (Frances Copeland), 1939-1943; 21 items (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 25)
    - International Relations Speakers Bureau, 1940; 2 items (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 26)
    - Open Forum Speakers Bureau, 1942-1944; 13 items (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 27)
    - Lectures, 1954-1956; 12 items (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 28)
  - Correspondence of Walter M. Kotschnig during his years with the Department of State and the United Nations, 1937-1977; 1948-1972; 2.7; 585 folders
    Most of Kotschnig's correspondence from his years with the U.S. Department of State and the United Nations Economic and Social Council remained with the Department of State. This series contains personal or unclassified correspondence from these years (circa 2320 items), including correspondence with: Ragnar Arnesen (UN Fund for Drug Abuse Control), Senator William Benton, George Bush, James Frederick Green, Elizabeth (Brad) Heffelfinger, Charles A. Judd (League of Nations Union), Vladimir Kuševic, Durward V. Sandifer, Carl W. A. Schurmann, Gilbert E. Yates, as well as correspondence concerning ECAFE (Economic Council for Asia and the Far East) and UNIDO (United Nations International Symposium on Industrial Development).
    - Abbott, Isabel R., 1953; 1 item (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 29)
    - Abram, Morris B., 1965; 2 items (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 30)
    - Abrams, George S., 1967; 1 item (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 31)
    - Achelis, Elisabeth, 1949; 1 item (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 32)
    - Acheson, David C., 1972; 2 items (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 33)
    - Acsay, L. E., 1951; 1 item (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 34)
    - Adiseshiah, Malcolm S., 1967; 1 item (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 35)
    - Alger, Chadwick F., 1973; 2 items (Box 6 (2-Correspondence), Folder 36)